Bomber drones like this are increasingly
being used for running logistics
missions inside Ukraine's kill zone.
Now, this beast is known as the Perun
Max, and at $25,000
a pop, this is one of the biggest drones
in the Ukrainian army at the moment.
This is used for logistics supplies and
bomber missions as well.
As you can see, it comes with Starlink,
GPS satellite navigation, but if that
fails, it's got optical navigation as
well. And this is just another example
of the incredible innovation that is
transforming
warfare here in Ukraine.
Perun Max drones already spend around
half of their time providing delivery
services.
They can carry loads of up to 45 kg over
a distance of 15 km.
With the zone close to the front line
proving so deadly, Ukraine aims to
replace 100% of logistics missions here
with uncrewed systems.
But drones like the Max still serve a
crucial role as bombers.
Underneath, you can strap three shells
or one larger shell.
They have recently started dropping old
155-mm shells deemed unsafe to fire from
artillery barrels onto Russian
positions.
Perun also manufactures a mid-size
bomber as well as the mini, which has a
range of about 20 km and is mainly used
for reconnaissance.
You can read more at
businessinsider.com.